{"sourceUrl": "https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019/advice-for-public/myth-busters", "sourceName": "WHOMyth", "sourceDate": 1586027132.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586027132.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586027133.258314, "questionText": "Exposing yourself to the sun or to temperatures higher than 25C degrees DOES NOT prevent the coronavirus disease ( COVID-19 )", "answerText": "You can catch COVID-19 , no matter how sunny or hot the weather is . Countries with hot weather have reported cases of COVID-19 . To protect yourself , make sure you clean your hands frequently and thoroughly and avoid touching your eyes , mouth , and nose .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "42532718-76a7-11ea-b6ac-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "42541b30-76a7-11ea-828a-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "42541c28-76a7-11ea-b138-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Myths"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019/advice-for-public/myth-busters", "sourceName": "WHOMyth", "sourceDate": 1586027132.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586027132.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586027134.0472589, "questionText": "You can recover from the coronavirus disease ( COVID-19 ) . Catching the new coronavirus DOES NOT mean you will have it for life .", "answerText": "Most of the people who catch COVID-19 can recover and eliminate the virus from their bodies . If you catch the disease , make sure you treat your symptoms . If you have cough , fever , and difficulty breathing , seek medical care early – but call your health facility by telephone first . Most patients recover thanks to supportive care .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "42cb8936-76a7-11ea-b7f8-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "42cb8a08-76a7-11ea-a3b4-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "42cb8a4c-76a7-11ea-8da5-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Myths"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019/advice-for-public/myth-busters", "sourceName": "WHOMyth", "sourceDate": 1586027132.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586027132.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586027134.797993, "questionText": "Being able to hold your breath for 10 seconds or more without coughing or feeling discomfort DOES NOT mean you are free from the coronavirus disease ( COVID-19 ) or any other lung disease .", "answerText": "The most common symptoms of COVID-19 are dry cough , tiredness and fever . Some people may develop more severe forms of the disease , such as pneumonia . The best way to confirm if you have   the virus producing COVID-19 disease is with a laboratory test .   You can not confirm it with this breathing exercise , which can even be dangerous .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "433e16c2-76a7-11ea-9dba-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "433e178a-76a7-11ea-b8b4-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "433e17d0-76a7-11ea-adf8-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Myths"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019/advice-for-public/myth-busters", "sourceName": "WHOMyth", "sourceDate": 1586027132.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586027132.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586027135.569978, "questionText": "Drinking alcohol does not protect you against COVID-19 and can be dangerous", "answerText": "Frequent or excessive alcohol consumption can increase your risk of health problems .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "43b3e276-76a7-11ea-aba8-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "43b3e348-76a7-11ea-a40d-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "43b3e38c-76a7-11ea-8141-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Myths"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019/advice-for-public/myth-busters", "sourceName": "WHOMyth", "sourceDate": 1586027132.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586027132.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586027136.3109262, "questionText": "COVID-19 virus can be transmitted in areas with hot and humid climates", "answerText": "From the evidence so far , the COVID-19 virus can be transmitted in ALL AREAS , including areas with hot and humid weather . Regardless of climate , adopt protective measures if you live in , or travel to an area reporting COVID-19 . The best way to protect yourself against COVID-19 is by frequently cleaning your hands . By doing this you eliminate viruses that may be on your hands and avoid infection that could occur by then touching your eyes , mouth , and nose .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "4424f1b4-76a7-11ea-9c99-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "4424f286-76a7-11ea-b80f-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "4424f2c2-76a7-11ea-9c6b-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Myths"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019/advice-for-public/myth-busters", "sourceName": "WHOMyth", "sourceDate": 1586027132.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586027132.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586027137.047381, "questionText": "Cold weather and snow CANNOT kill the new coronavirus .", "answerText": "There is no reason to believe that cold weather can kill the new coronavirus or other diseases . The normal human body temperature remains around 36.5 ° C to 37 ° C , regardless of the external temperature or weather . The most effective way to protect yourself against the new coronavirus is by frequently cleaning your hands with alcohol - based hand rub or washing them with soap and water .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "4495517a-76a7-11ea-a89a-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "44955238-76a7-11ea-8f19-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "4495527e-76a7-11ea-a132-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Myths"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019/advice-for-public/myth-busters", "sourceName": "WHOMyth", "sourceDate": 1586027132.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586027132.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586027137.802974, "questionText": "Taking a hot bath does not prevent the new coronavirus disease", "answerText": "Taking a hot bath will not prevent you from catching COVID-19 . Your normal body temperature remains around 36.5 ° C to 37 ° C , regardless of the temperature of your bath or shower . Actually , taking a hot bath with extremely hot water can be harmful , as it can burn you . The best way to protect yourself against COVID-19 is by frequently cleaning your hands . By doing this you eliminate viruses that may be on your hands and avoid infection that could occur by then touching your eyes , mouth , and nose .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "45089cd4-76a7-11ea-b277-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "45089d9c-76a7-11ea-aa0e-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "45089de2-76a7-11ea-93d2-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Myths"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019/advice-for-public/myth-busters", "sourceName": "WHOMyth", "sourceDate": 1586027132.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586027132.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586027138.543235, "questionText": "The new coronavirus CANNOT be transmitted through mosquito bites .", "answerText": "To date there has been no information nor evidence to suggest that the new coronavirus could be transmitted by mosquitoes . The new coronavirus is a respiratory virus which spreads primarily through droplets generated when an infected person coughs or sneezes , or through droplets of saliva or discharge from the nose . To protect yourself , clean your hands frequently with an alcohol - based hand rub or wash them with soap and water . Also , avoid close contact with anyone who is coughing and sneezing .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "4579913a-76a7-11ea-82bc-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "45799206-76a7-11ea-ad49-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "4579924a-76a7-11ea-b0cb-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Myths"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019/advice-for-public/myth-busters", "sourceName": "WHOMyth", "sourceDate": 1586027132.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586027132.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586027139.280884, "questionText": "Are hand dryers effective in killing the new coronavirus ?", "answerText": "No . Hand dryers are not effective in killing the 2019-nCoV. To protect yourself against the new coronavirus , you should frequently clean your hands with an alcohol - based hand rub or wash them with soap and water . Once your hands are cleaned , you should dry them thoroughly by using paper towels or a warm air dryer .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "45ea1fa6-76a7-11ea-b34f-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "45ea205a-76a7-11ea-95ec-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "45ea209e-76a7-11ea-bafb-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Myths"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019/advice-for-public/myth-busters", "sourceName": "WHOMyth", "sourceDate": 1586027132.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586027132.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586027140.0188, "questionText": "Can an ultraviolet disinfection lamp kill the new coronavirus ?", "answerText": "UV lamps should not be used to sterilize hands or other areas of skin as UV radiation can cause skin irritation .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "465ab888-76a7-11ea-9065-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "465ab946-76a7-11ea-8825-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "465ab98c-76a7-11ea-8d7f-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Myths"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019/advice-for-public/myth-busters", "sourceName": "WHOMyth", "sourceDate": 1586027132.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586027132.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586027140.754655, "questionText": "How effective are thermal scanners in detecting people infected with the new coronavirus ?", "answerText": "Thermal scanners are effective in detecting people who have developed a fever ( i.e. have a higher than normal body temperature ) because of infection with the new coronavirus . However , they can not detect people who are infected but are not yet sick with fever . This is because it takes between 2 and 10 days before people who are infected become sick and develop a fever .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "46cb00d4-76a7-11ea-976b-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "46cb019c-76a7-11ea-a28b-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "46cb01d8-76a7-11ea-8131-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Myths"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019/advice-for-public/myth-busters", "sourceName": "WHOMyth", "sourceDate": 1586027132.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586027132.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586027141.493231, "questionText": "Can spraying alcohol or chlorine all over your body kill the new coronavirus ?", "answerText": "No . Spraying alcohol or chlorine all over your body will not kill viruses that have already entered your body . Spraying such substances can be harmful to clothes or mucous membranes ( i.e. eyes , mouth ) . Be aware that both alcohol and chlorine can be useful to disinfect surfaces , but they need to be used under appropriate recommendations .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "473bb37e-76a7-11ea-b1b5-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "473bb43a-76a7-11ea-9817-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "473bb482-76a7-11ea-bb94-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Myths"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019/advice-for-public/myth-busters", "sourceName": "WHOMyth", "sourceDate": 1586027132.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586027132.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586027142.218143, "questionText": "Do vaccines against pneumonia protect you against the new coronavirus ?", "answerText": "No . Vaccines against pneumonia , such as pneumococcal vaccine and Haemophilus influenza type B ( Hib ) vaccine , do not provide protection against the new coronavirus . The virus is so new and different that it needs its own vaccine . Researchers are trying to develop a vaccine against 2019-nCoV , and WHO is supporting their efforts . Although these vaccines are not effective against 2019-nCoV , vaccination against respiratory illnesses is highly recommended to protect your health .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "47aa505e-76a7-11ea-bc1b-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "47aa5130-76a7-11ea-8627-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "47aa5176-76a7-11ea-beb7-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Myths"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019/advice-for-public/myth-busters", "sourceName": "WHOMyth", "sourceDate": 1586027132.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586027132.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586027142.935494, "questionText": "Can regularly rinsing your nose with saline help prevent infection with the new coronavirus ?", "answerText": "No . There is no evidence that regularly rinsing the nose with saline has protected people from infection with the new coronavirus . There is some limited evidence that regularly rinsing nose with saline can help people recover more quickly from the common cold . However , regularly rinsing the nose has not been shown to prevent respiratory infections .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "4817c5da-76a7-11ea-8058-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "4817c6ac-76a7-11ea-ae44-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "4817c6f4-76a7-11ea-b464-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Myths"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019/advice-for-public/myth-busters", "sourceName": "WHOMyth", "sourceDate": 1586027132.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586027132.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586027143.6609569, "questionText": "Can eating garlic help prevent infection with the new coronavirus ?", "answerText": "Garlic is a healthy food that may have some antimicrobial properties . However , there is no evidence from the current outbreak that eating garlic has protected people from the new coronavirus .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "4886784a-76a7-11ea-9e6f-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "48867908-76a7-11ea-b8fb-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "4886794c-76a7-11ea-9ac5-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Myths"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019/advice-for-public/myth-busters", "sourceName": "WHOMyth", "sourceDate": 1586027132.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586027132.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586027144.380328, "questionText": "Does the new coronavirus affect older people , or are younger people also susceptible ?", "answerText": "People of all ages can be infected by the new coronavirus ( 2019-nCoV ) . Older people , and people with pre - existing medical conditions ( such as asthma , diabetes , heart disease ) appear to be more vulnerable to becoming severely ill with the virus . WHO advises people of all ages to take steps to protect themselves from the virus , for example by following good hand hygiene and good respiratory hygiene .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "48f43cb8-76a7-11ea-81ae-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "48f43d80-76a7-11ea-9b8e-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "48f43dc6-76a7-11ea-a1ba-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Myths"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019/advice-for-public/myth-busters", "sourceName": "WHOMyth", "sourceDate": 1586027132.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586027132.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586027145.100868, "questionText": "Are antibiotics effective in preventing and treating the new coronavirus ?", "answerText": "No , antibiotics do not work against viruses , only bacteria . The new coronavirus ( 2019-nCoV ) is a virus and , therefore , antibiotics should not be used as a means of prevention or treatment . However , if you are hospitalized for the 2019-nCoV , you may receive antibiotics because bacterial co - infection is possible .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "49622ed0-76a7-11ea-88c1-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "49622f86-76a7-11ea-bc64-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "49622fca-76a7-11ea-a4bc-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Myths"}
{"sourceUrl": "https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019/advice-for-public/myth-busters", "sourceName": "WHOMyth", "sourceDate": 1586027132.0, "lastUpdateTime": 1586027132.0, "needUpdate": true, "typeOfInfo": "QA", "isAnnotated": false, "responseAuthority": "", "hasAnswer": true, "targetEducationLevel": "NA", "extraData": {}, "dateScraped": 1586027145.83061, "questionText": "Are there any specific medicines to prevent or treat the new coronavirus ?", "answerText": "To date , there is no specific medicine recommended to prevent or treat the new coronavirus ( 2019-nCoV).However , those infected with the virus should receive appropriate care to relieve and treat symptoms , and those with severe illness should receive optimized supportive care . Some specific treatments are under investigation , and will be tested through clinical trials . WHO is helping to accelerate research and development efforts with a range or partners .", "containsURLs": false, "questionUUID": "49d18852-76a7-11ea-9b97-3af9d3ce0829", "answerUUID": "49d18924-76a7-11ea-9516-3af9d3ce0829", "exampleUUID": "49d18968-76a7-11ea-b311-3af9d3ce0829", "topic": "Myths"}
